Guide to the Frederick Emmons Terman Papers SC0160
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Professional Organizations, 1934-1977; Series IV
  - AMERICAN INSTITUTE OF ELECTRICAL ENGINEERS
    - Communications, Committee on. 1934 - 38. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Communications, Committee on. 1939 - 42. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Convention, 1939 (San Francisco). 1937 - 39. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Convention, 1940 (New York). 1939 - 40. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Research, Committee on. 1947 - 49. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Education, Committee on. 1935 - 41. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - AMERICAN SOCIETY FOR ENGINEERING EDUCATION
    - General Correspondence. 1946 - 51. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence. 1956 - 71. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Engineering College Administrative Council. 1946 48. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Engineering College Administrative Council. 1949. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Engineering College Administrative Council. 1950. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Engineering College Administrative Council. 1951. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Engineering College Administrative Council. Manpower Committee. 1950 - 51. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Engineering College Administrative Council. Military Affairs Committee. 1950 - 51. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Engineering College Administrative Council. Nominating Committee. 1951. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Engineering College Administrative Council. Committees, miscellaneous. 1949. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Engineering College Administrative Council. Committees, miscellaneous. 1950 - 51. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Engineering College Administrative Council. Meeting. Kansas City. 1949. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Engineering College Administrative Council. Meeting. Seattle. 1950. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Engineering College Administrative Council.Meeting. Washington. 1950. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Engineering College Administrative Council. Program Plans. 1951. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Engineering College Research Council. 1946 - 48. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Engineering College Research Council. 1949 - 50. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Engineering College Research Council. 1951. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Engineering Manpower Statistics Committee. 1968 76. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Executive Board. June 1949 - May 1950. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Executive Board. June 1950 - June 1951. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Institutional Development, Committee for. 1965 67. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Lamme Award Committee. 1969 - 72. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Terman Award. 1969. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Terman Award. 1970. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Terman Award. 1971. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Terman Award. 1972. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Terman Award. 1973. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Terman Award. 1974. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Terman Award. 1975. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Terman Award. 1976. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Terman Award. 1977. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - INSTITUTE OF ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS
    - General Correspondence. 1963 - 64. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence. 1965 - 66. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - General Correspondence. 1967 - 69. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - General Correspondence. 1970 - 71. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - General Correspondence. 1972 - 73. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - General Correspondence. 1974. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Awards. 1970 - 73. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Founders Award (to Hewlett and Packard). 1972 73. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - History Committee. 1969 - 70. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - History Committee. 1971 - 72. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - History Committee. 1973. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - History Committee. 1974. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - History Committee. 1975 - 77. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - History Committee. Alger, Philip correspondence. 1972 - 74. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - History Committee. Bicentennial Project (Harold Chestnut proposal). (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - History Committee. Bicentennial Publication Project (James Brittain). 1973 - 75-. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - History Committee. Farmer, Moses. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - History Committee. Hughes, Thomas correspondence and lists. 1972 - 74. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - History Committee. Membership. 1972 - 74. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - History Committee. Oral History Project (Frank Polkinghorn). 1972 - 74. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - History Committee. Report. 1974. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - History Committee. Smithsonian Institution Correspondence. 1972 - 74. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Life Member Fund Committee. 1970 - 71. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Life Member Fund Committee. 1972. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Life Member Fund Committee. 1973 - 74. (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Life Member Fund Committee. Annual Meeting Agenda. 1971. (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Life Member Fund Committee. Annual Meeting Agenda. 1972. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Life Member Fund Committee. Finances. 1966 - 71. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Life Member Fund Committee. Keyes, William. 1971 - 72. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Life Member Fund Committee. Mailings. 1972. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Life Member Fund Committee. Membership. 1970 - 71. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Life Member Fund Committee. Suggestions for projects. 1971 - 72. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Life Member Yearbook/Directory. 1972 73. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Spectrum articles. 1973. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Spectrum articles. 1974. (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Spectrum articles. 1976. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - INSTITUTE OF RADIO ENGINEERS
    - General Correspondence. 1934 - 36. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence. 1937 - 39. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - General Correspondence. 1940. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - General Correspondence. 1941. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - General Correspondence. 1942. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - General Correspondence. 1943. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - General Correspondence. 1944. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - General Correspondence. 1945. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - General Correspondence. 1946. (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - General Correspondence. 1947 - 48. (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - General Correspondence. Jan. 1949 - June 1950. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence. Sept. 1950 - Aug. 1952. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - General Correspondence. 1953 - 55. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - General Correspondence. 1956 - 59. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - General Correspondence. 1960 - 61. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - General Correspondence. 1962. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Accountant's Report. 1941. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Accountant's Report. 1947. (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Accountant's Report. 1948. (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Admissions Committee. 1941 - 42. (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Annual Review Committee. 1946 - 47. (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Awards Committee. 1940. (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Awards Committee. 1942 - 44. (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Chicago Section. 1940 - 41. (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Code of Administrative Practice. 1941. (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Constitution and Laws Committee. 1946 - 47. (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Constitutional Amendments. 1941. (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Conventions: 1937 (Spokane). Aug. 1936 -April 1937. (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Conventions: 1937 (Spokane). May - June 1937. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Conventions: 1937 (Spokane). July - August 1937. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Conventions: 1937 (Spokane). Undated material and fragments. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Conventions: 1938 (Portland). Feb. - May 1938. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Conventions: 1939 (San Francisco). Oct. 1938 -Feb. 1939. (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Conventions: 1939 (San Francisco). March 1939. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Conventions: 1939 (San Francisco). April 1939. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Conventions: 1939 (San Francisco). May - Aug. 1939. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Conventions: 1940 (Los Angeles). Aug. 1939-Dec. 1940. (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Conventions: 1941 (New York, Detroit). 1940 42. (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Conventions: 1941 (Seattle). 1940 - 41. (Box 11, Folder I)
    - Conventions: 1947 (San Francisco). 1947. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Conventions: 1948 (Los Angeles). 1948 - 49. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Conventions: 1949 (San Francisco). 1949. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Conventions: 1951 (San Francisco). 1950 - 51. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Directors, Board of. 1939 - 40. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Directors, Board of. 1941. (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Directors, Board of. 1942. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Directors, Board of. Jan. - April 1943. (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Directors, Board of. May - Sept. 1943. (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Directors, Board of. Oct. - Dec. 1943. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Directors, Board of. Oct. 1947 - Nov. 1948. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Directors, Board of. Jan. 1949 - Jan. 1950. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Education Committee. 1949 - 50. (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Election (Presidency). 1940. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Electronics Committee. 1936 - 40. (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Executive Committee. Minutes. 1941. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Executive Committee. Supporting documents. 1941. (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Executive Committee. 1942. (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Executive Committee. 1943. (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Executive Committee. 1948. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Executive Committee. Jan. 1949 - Jan. 1950. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Handbook Committee. 1945 - 48. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Membership Committee. 1938 - 40. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Membership Committee. Jan. - July 1941. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Membership Committee. Aug. - Sept. 1941. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Membership Committee. Oct. - Dec. 1941. (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Membership Committee. 1942 - 43. (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Membership Committee. 1949 - 51. (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Membership: John M. Clayton correspondence. 1941. (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Membership: Professors. 1941. (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Membership: Statistics and data. 1942. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Membership: Students. 1938 - 40. (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Membership: Students. Undated material. c. 1938 40. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Membership: Students. 1940 - 42. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Membership: Students. 1948 - 50. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Membership: Students. Manual for Institute Representatives. 1950. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Membership survey. 1941. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - New Sections. 1940 - 42. (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - New York Section. 1940 - 41. (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Nominations Committee. 1951 - 52. (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Nominations Committee. 1953-; 1955. (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Office re-organization. 1941. (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Policy Development Committee. 1948 49. (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Pratt, Haraden. 1941. (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Presidency. 1940 - 41. (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Proceedings. 1941 - 42. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Proceedings: Advertising Campaign. 1940 - 42. (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Proceedings: Advertising Solicitation. 1941. (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Regional Director. Oct. 1947 - Aug. 1948. (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Professional Groups Committee. 1947 - 48. (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Regional Director. Sept. - Dec. 1948. (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Regional Director. Jan. - May 1949. (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Regional Director. June - Dec. 1949. (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Regional Director. 1954 - 55; 1957. (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Reports, miscellaneous. 1941; 1948; 1949. (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Research Committee. 1945 - 48. (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - San Francisco Section. 1938 - 41. (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Secretary's Report. 1939. (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Secretary's Report. 1940. (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Secretary's Report. 1941. (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Secretary's Report. 1942. (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Secretary's Report. 1947. (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Secretary's Report. 1948. (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Secretary's Report. 1949. (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Secretary's Report. 1950. (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Sections Committee. 1941. (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Standards Committee. 1947. (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Travel. 1941. (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - INSTITUTE FOR SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY IN NEW JERSEY
    - General Correspondence. 1965 - 66. (Box 17, Folder I)
    - General Correspondence. Jan. - May 1967. (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - General Correspondence. June 1967 - 1969. (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Background Materials. 1965 - 66. (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Brochures. c. 1965 - 66. (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Bylaws and Charter. 1966. (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Expenses. 1966. (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Expenses - Industry Committee. 1965 - 66. (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Millman, Sidney. 1965 - 66. (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Minutes. 1966 - 67; 1969. (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - President. 1967. (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Report. Sept. 1965. (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Report. Oct. 1965. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Report. June 1966. (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Report: Worksheets. 1966. (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Statements of purposes and goals. 1966. (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Supplementary memos. Sept. 1966. (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Working materials: corporations. 1965 - 66. (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Working materials: library and departments. 1965 66. (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Working materials: finances. 1965 - 66. (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Working materials: U.S. Government. 1965 - 66. (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Working materials: miscellaneous. 1965 - 66. (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - SIGMA XI (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - General Correspondence. 1955 - 58. (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence. 1967. (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - General Correspondence. 1968. (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - General Correspondence. 1969. (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - General Correspondence. 1970. (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - General Correspondence. 1973. (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - General Correspondence. 1974. (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - General Correspondence. Jan. - June 1975. (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - SIGMA XI
    - General Correspondence. July - Dec. 1975. (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - General Correspondence. 1976. (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Amendments to the Constitution, Committee on. 1973. (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Budget Committee. 1975. (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Building Fund. 1974 - 75. (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Committee Appointments. 1974. (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Conventions Committee. 1967 - 69. (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Directors, Board of. Meeting, June 1973. (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Directors, Board of. Meeting, Oct. 1973. (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Directors, Board of. Meeting, Jan. 1974. (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Directors, Board of. Meeting, April 1974. (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Directors, Board of. Meeting, Nov. 1974. (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Directors, Board of. Meeting, Feb. 1975. (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Directors, Board of. Meeting, June 1975. (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Directors, Board of. Meeting, Oct., Nov. 1975. (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Directors, Board of. Meeting, Feb. 1976. (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Directors, Board of. Meeting, June 1976. (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Directors, Board of. Meeting, Nov. 1976. (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Executive Committee Meeting. Dec. 1966. (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Executive Committee Meetings. March, Sept., Dec. 1967. (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Executive Committee Meetings. March 1968. (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Executive Committee Meetings. July, Oct. 1968. (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Executive Committee Meetings. Jan., June 1969. (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Executive Committee Meetings. June 1970. (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Executive Committee Meetings. Oct. 1970. (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Executive Committee Meetings. Feb. 1976. (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Executive Committee Meetings. May 1976. (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Finance Committee. 1971 - 73. (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Finance Committee. 1974. (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Finance Committee. 1975. (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Financial Information. 1976. (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Grinter, Linton E. (President). 1974. (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Installation ritual. 1974. (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Installation. F. E. Terman's speeches. 1973 - 74. (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - installations - miscellaneous. 1967 - 68; 1970. (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - International Chapter. 1974. (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - International Chapter. 1976. (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Lectureships, Committee on. 1966; 1973. (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Long Range Planning Committee. 1970 - 72. (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Long Range Planning Committee. Jan. - Feb. 1973. (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Long Range Planning Committee. May 1973. (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Long Range Planning Committee. 1974. (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Long Range Planning Committee. Jan. - June 1975. (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - "Lost" Stanford alumni. 1971 72. (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Long Range Planning Committee. July 1975 - June 1976. (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Membership problem. 1975. (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Motto. 1968. (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - National meeting, 1966 (Washington, D.C.). (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - National meeting, 1967 (Portsmouth). (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - National meeting, 1968 (Portsmouth). (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - National meeting, 1969 (Palm Springs). (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - National meeting, 1970 (Palm Springs). (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - National meeting, 1972 (Myrtle Beach). (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - National meeting, 1973 (Fontana). (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - National meeting, 1973 (Fontana). Reports of committees and proceedings. (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - National meeting, 1974 (Fredericksburg). (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - National meeting, 1975 (Fredericksburg). (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - National meeting, 1976 (Hershey). (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - New Clubs and Chapters. Bowling Green State University. 1975. (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - New Clubs and Chapters. Herbert Lehmann College. 1974. (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - New Clubs and Chapters. Medical College of Georgia. 1974. (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - New Clubs and Chapters. New Jersey Institute of Technology. 1975. (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - New Clubs and Chapters. Oakland University. 1974. (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - New Clubs and Chapters. Portland State University. 1972 - 74. (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - New Clubs and Chapters. Southern Methodist University. 1974 - 75. (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - New Clubs and Chapters. University of Dayton, 1970; 1973 - 74. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - New Clubs and Chapters. University of Texas, Arlington. 1969 - 70. (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - New Clubs and Chapters. University of Texas, El Paso. 1971 - 72. (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - New Clubs and Chapters. University of Texas, El Paso. 1973 - 75. (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - New Clubs and Chapters. University of Toledo. 1975. (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - New Clubs and Chapters. Miscellaneous. 1974 76. (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - News and Newsletter. 1973 - 76. (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Nominations Committee. 1972. (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Nominations Committee. 1975. (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - President's message, American Scientist masthead. 1975. (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Regions, Committee on. 1973 - 75. (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Role of Sigma Xi in the Public Understanding of Science, Ad Hoc Committee on, 1975 - 76. (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Science and Society Committee. 1975. (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Seeger, Raymond. 1974 - 75. (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Southwest Region (including Stanford). 1973 74. (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Southwest Region Meeting. 1976. (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Stanford Chapter. 1973 - 74: (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Stanford Chapter. Activities. 1969 - 75. (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Stanford Chapter. Finances. 1972 - 74. (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Stanford Chapter. History. 1976. (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Travel Expenses. 1973 - 74. (Box 26, Folder 14)
- Patents, Consulting, and Research, 1923-1978; Series V
  Box 1-Box 3, folder 5: Patent applications, 1926-40. Dr. Terman's invention disclosures; correspondence with attorneys; and correspondence with the U.S. Patent Office to obtain letters of patent for various electronic devices and systems. The files are arranged alphabetically by subject, and chronologically within each folder.
  Box 3, folder 6-Box 4: Correspondence and negotiations, 1928-35. Correspondence negotiating sale of Terman's patent rights to various individuals and companies. The folders are arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent or company.
  Boxes 5-10: Miscellaneous consulting, 1928-78. These boxes contain papers documenting Dr. Terman's commercial consulting career as a technical advisor, or in some patent cases, as an expert witness,-for various individuals and companies including Cyril Elwell, Encyclopedia Britannica, Federal Telegraph, General Electric, Gilfillan Brothers, and Heintz and Kaufman. These folders are arranged alphabetically by the name of the company or individual.
  Of particular interest in this group are the papers related to the Television shares Management Company (Box 6, folder 9 -Box 10), an investment firm specializing in electronics and other high technology stocks. From 1948 to 1978, Dr. Terman was a scientific advisor to the company, keeping it abreast of the latest technological developments that might affect stock performance. In this capacity, he wrote monthly reports on electronics activities in the Bay Area that will be useful to researcher in the hisory of technology.
  Box 11: Miscellaneous research materials, 1923-39. Dr. Terman's student reports and papers; laboratory notebooks; and notarized papers related to his personal research.
  - PATENTS
    - Applications: Electric Detector and Frequency Changing System. 1926 - 32. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Applications: Electrical Measuring Instrument. 1927 - 33. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Applications: Frequency Changing System. 1930 - 35. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Applications: Frequency Multiplier. 1926 - 34. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Applications: High Efficiency Amplifier. 1936 - 40. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Applications: Inductance Coils. 1926 - 32. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Applications: Loss Metering Circuit. 1929 - 33. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Applications: Method of Adjacent Channel Transmission. 1932 - 33. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Applications: Modulation Meter. 1931 - 33. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Applications: Multirange Meter. 1936 - 39. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Applications: Oscillating Radio Receiver. 1933 - 35. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Applications: Radio Receiving System. 1931 - 36. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Applications: Signaling System. 1929 - 32. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Applications: Thermionic Tube. (No. 532,742). 1930 34. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Applications: Thermionic Tube. (No. 546,024). 1931 34. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Applications: Thermionic Tube. (No. 546,025). 1931 34. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Applications: Variable Reactance Circuit. 1930 - 35. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Applications: Variable Vacuum Tube Resistor. 1931 - 35. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Applications - abandoned: Chain Broadcasting System. 1930 - 31. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Applications - abandoned: Frequency Changing and Amplifying System. 1926 - 28. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Applications - abandoned: Frequency Changing System. 1927 - 29. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Applications - abandoned: Frequency Increasing Superheterodyne. 1926. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Applications - abandoned: Method and Apparatus for Frequency Changing and Amplifying. 1926 - 31. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Applications - abandoned: Radio Frequency Amplifier. 1926 - 29. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Applications - abandoned: Rectifying System. 1927 - 32. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Applications - abandoned: Sum Frequency Receiver. 1926. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence and Negotiations: Elwell, Cyril F. 1932 - 37. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence and Negotiations: Federal Telegraph Company. 1929 - 31. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence and Negotiations: Hazeltine Corporation. 1935. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence and Negotiations: Heintz and Kaufman. 1934 - 37. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence and Negotiations: Hickock Electrical Instrument Co. 1935. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence and Negotiations: ITT and Subsidiaries. 1942 - 45. (Box 3, Folder 11)